Cherammoya, atamoya, custard apple. All
similar names for fruit that are quite
similar. These are atamoyas. And today
we are going to make these into a
delicious gelato in the ninja creamy. So
the cheramoya is an actual custard
apple. These aren't cheramoyers. Custard
apple has been described as the most
delicious fruit in the world by Mark
Twain. Uh they're also known as the ice
cream fruit, the custard fruit. lots of
different variations. They are also
known as an anon, a citaphile, and a
scria. But an atamoya is a hybrid. It's
a hybrid between a cheramoya and a sugar
apple. And generally, these are much
sweeter with a much more delicious
custard kind of texture. You have to
wait for them to ripen. So, they go
quite soft like
avocados. You will that when I bought
these, they were quite hard. So, a few
days, three or four days, and they start
to soften up where you put your thumb
down on the edge, give it a little
squeeze, and it gives quite easily. I
could probably leave these for another
couple of days. To be fair, I don't
think they're quite ripe enough to eat
just yet. So, so I'm going to leave
these and enjoy these
independently later on,
but sugar content is about 14 g per 100
g. So, about 14% sugar content, which is
pretty much the same as a mango. So, we
can treat this in a similar respect to a
mango. And that's what we're going to
do. First thing we need to do is talk
about the ingredients that we need for
this
atamoya/ custard apple gelato. You're
going to need 375 g of custard apple
flesh. Atamoya flesh. That equates to
about three ripe fruit. 321 g of whole
milk. 254 g of whipping cream or heavy
cream. 128 g of sugar, 45 g of glucose
syrup. You can use corn syrup or golden
syrup, 55 g of skim milk powder, and
we're going to use 2 g of guag gum. Cold
process. This is going to be different.
We're not heating this up. We are
blending this into the delicious mix.
We're going to process in here. So, the
first thing we need to do is get the
flesh out of our custard apples. When
they're ripe, they can be quite This can
be quite a dirty process. So, if you
want to wear gloves, do that. But
otherwise, you get the smell of that
custard, apple flesh, and flesh coming
out. Loads of seeds in these. So, make
sure you get all of those seeds out. But
those three fruit gave me just shy of
400 g worth of usable flesh. Don't use
the outside. That is not good for you.
just that super soft creamy whitish
flesh
inside. With all that, we're going to
add everything into a blender. We're
going to make sure that we stir our
guard, so our stabilizer in with our
sugars to completely break apart any of
those clumps. And within the blender, we
are going to fire that up and do it on
low for 1 minute and then on high for a
minute or two. We want this as smooth as
we possibly can. After we've processed
this, we're going to run this through a
fine mesh sie and get any little
particles left out. And as you can see,
there's just a few little specks of seed
casing, etc. come out of here. But it
really isn't too bad. So, now that we've
got that processed, we're going to put
that into our Ninja Creamy container and
get it in the freezer. This one's ready
to go. So, we've got everything here.
Let's get our Ninja Creamy tub out.
going
nice. We're going to turn this on to ice
cream setting and let it do its
thing. Right, process done. Let's see
how we got on. There we
go. Get rid of
this. Let's get some scooped up.
So there we go. Atamoya, cheramoya,
custard apple,
gelato. Oh, that's
incredible. That
flavor. That is delicious. Never had
this before in my
life. Super smooth texture. I mean,
incredibly smooth texture.
Really,
really, really nice
gelato. It's kind of got elements of
pineapple with a little touch of banana
in there. Little bit of normal apple in
there, like green apple. Granny Smith's
apple. I don't know, maybe a bit of
papaya in there, too. Yeah, that is
really nice. Really, really nice. I got
these fruit from my local supermarket or
one of my local supermarkets. you I know
you can get them in the UK in
um exotic fruit and veg markets. You can
get them in Bath in England. You can get
them in Bristol. You can get them in
Reading. That's so nice. It's really
difficult to describe that taste, but
it's like an all-encompassing tropical
kind of flavor. Really nice. Atamo grow
in Florida actually. So, you know, if
you're in the US, you'll have no problem
getting these. But you can also use
chermo. So, standard custard apples in
this recipe. I really recommend that you
go and find these weird kind of dragon
scale looking fruit from uh either your
local store, your somewhere that sells
exotic fruit online. You know, these
days you can go online and order exotic
fruit and have it delivered next day.
So, there's no really no kind of excuse
to not try things like this. Really,
really nice. They look weird as
when you're dealing with them and taking
the flesh out and getting rid of all
those seeds. Let me show you how many
seeds come out of those three
fruit. Those seeds
we all of those seeds
probably 70 plus seeds came out of those
three fruits. So there's loads of seeds
in there and you've got to just like put
it in your hand and just squeeze it and
the seeds come out. But I'm going to
grow these. So, if you want to see how I
get on turning these into small atamoya
fruit trees, then subscribe to my other
channel, The Hydro Lifestyle. I'll put a
link on the screen here. There's a link
in the description as well. And I'm
going to just polish this off because
it's 5 8 in the morning on a
Thursday. And I'm going to go for a
paddle in Spray Lakes Reservoir um with
my buddy. So, I hope you enjoyed this
video and I will see you next week.